export const chapter = "Chapter - 6: Teeth and Their care ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "What is the main purpose of teeth in the digestion process?",
          optionA: "To protect the gums",
          optionB: "To give shape to the face",
          optionC: "To grind food and initiate digestion",
          correctAnswer: "To grind food and initiate digestion",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How many sets of teeth do humans have during their lifetime?",
          optionA: "One",
          optionB: "Two",
          optionC: "Three",
          correctAnswer: "Two",
        },
        {
          question: "When do milk teeth start growing in a baby's mouth?",
          optionA: "At birth",
          optionB: "At six months",
          optionC: "At two and a half years",
          correctAnswer: "At six months",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the visible part of the tooth above the gums called?",
          optionA: "Neck",
          optionB: "Root",
          optionC: "Crown",
          correctAnswer: "Crown",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which part of the tooth contains nerves and blood vessels?",
          optionA: "Enamel",
          optionB: "Dentine",
          optionC: "Pulp",
          correctAnswer: "Pulp",
        },
        {
          question: "How many teeth are there in a permanent set of teeth?",
          optionA: "20",
          optionB: "28",
          optionC: "32",
          correctAnswer: "32",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the function of enamel in a tooth?",
          optionA: "Absorbs pressure",
          optionB: "Protects from wear and tear",
          optionC: "Nourishes the tooth",
          correctAnswer: "Protects from wear and tear",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What can happen if food particles are not cleaned from the teeth?",
          optionA: "Toothache",
          optionB: "Formation of plaque",
          optionC: "Gums become stronger",
          correctAnswer: "Formation of plaque",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the primary cause of tooth decay?",
          optionA: "Excessive brushing",
          optionB: "Harmful bacteria in plaque",
          optionC: "Lack of vitamin C",
          correctAnswer: "Harmful bacteria in plaque",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How can one protect teeth from decay, according to the given tips?",
          optionA: "Avoid dental check-ups",
          optionB: "Brush teeth only in the morning",
          optionC: "Use dental floss, brush regularly, and visit the dentist",
          correctAnswer:
            "Use dental floss, brush regularly, and visit the dentist",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Teeth play a crucial role in the ________ process by grinding food and mixing it with saliva.",
          optionA: "Digestive",
          optionB: "Chewing",
          optionC: "Absorption",
          correctAnswer: "Chewing",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The first set of teeth, known as milk teeth, starts growing when a baby is about ________ months old.",
          optionA: "Four",
          optionB: "Six",
          optionC: "Twelve",
          correctAnswer: "Six",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The structure of a tooth includes three main parts: crown, neck, and ________.",
          optionA: "Joint",
          optionB: "Shaft",
          optionC: "Root",
          correctAnswer: "Root",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Enamel, the white and hardest part of the tooth, protects the tooth from wear and tear caused by ________.",
          optionA: "Smiling",
          optionB: "Chewing",
          optionC: "Talking",
          correctAnswer: "Chewing",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Tooth decay results in bad breath, bleeding gums, toothache, and the formation of ________ on the surface of the teeth.",
          optionA: "Plaque",
          optionB: "Cavities",
          optionC: "Enamel",
          correctAnswer: "Cavities",
        },
        {
          question:
            "It is essential to brush our teeth twice daily, once in the morning and once before going to bed at night, to prevent ________ growth.",
          optionA: "Fungi",
          optionB: "Bacteria",
          optionC: "Viruses",
          correctAnswer: "Bacteria",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The soft part of the tooth that contains nerves and blood vessels is known as ________.",
          optionA: "Dentine",
          optionB: "Pulp",
          optionC: "Enamel",
          correctAnswer: "Pulp",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The visible part of the tooth above the gums is called the ________.",
          optionA: "Neck",
          optionB: "Crown",
          optionC: "Shaft",
          correctAnswer: "Crown",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The primary cause of tooth decay is the presence of harmful ________ in plaque.",
          optionA: "Fungi",
          optionB: "Bacteria",
          optionC: "Viruses",
          correctAnswer: "Bacteria",
        },
        {
          question:
            "To protect teeth from decay, it is advisable to eat fruits and vegetables rich in vitamin C, as they are healthy for teeth and ________.",
          optionA: "Gums",
          optionB: "Bones",
          optionC: "Joints",
          correctAnswer: "Gums",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "Teeth give shape to our face and make us look smart.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "The first set of teeth is called permanent teeth.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Enamel is the softest part of the tooth.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Tooth decay can result in bad breath, bleeding gums, and cavities.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Eastern Coastal Plains are wider than the Western Coastal Plains.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Northern Circars is the southern part of the Eastern Coastal Plains.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Andaman Islands are separated from the Nicobar Islands by the Ten Degree Channel.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "The Lakshadweep Islands are built of volcanic deposits.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Coromandel Coast is known for its rocky terrain and lighthouses.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "The neck is the visible part of the tooth above the gums.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
